### **HIEU MINH NGUYEN**

🗖 hieunguyenvn98@gmail.com · 📞 (+84) 9067659838 · 🗘 therealhieu · 🛅 nguyenminhhieu

Ambitous and enthusiastic Data Engineer with 2 years of experience in developing data pipelines and working with cloud technologies. I am passionate about building data products, solving technical and business problems, and utilizing both open-source and proprietary technologies to deliver the best solutions.

# EXPERIENCE

# Fossil Group, Inc

Ho Chi Minh, Vietnam Nov 2021 - Jul 2023

Data Engineer

Engineering:

- Engaged directly in Data Platform to do ETL, data validation and monitoring.
- Developed an ingestion API in Rust for mobile apps and watch apps to send data to Kafka. Some Rust crates used: actix-web, kafka-rust.
- A core member to rebuild Python-based Data Platform in Rust. Performance was improved by 10x in production. Some Rust crates used: arrow2, polars, duckdb-rs, tokio, tower, pyo3.
- Technologies: Kafka, S3, Redshift, BigQuery, Airflow, Spark, Great Expectations, Grafana

#### Analytics:

- Worked closely with Product team to define app tracking events and build dashboards.
- Technologies: Data Studio, BigQuery, Redshift, Athena.

#### Fossil Group, Inc

Ho Chi Minh, Vietnam

Data Engineer Intern

Feb 2020 - Aug 2020

Designed data warehouse, implemented data transformation and built analytics dashboards.

Technologies: Firebase, BigQuery, Redash, Athena, MongoDB, Google Data Studio

**Agilsun Co., LTD**Web Developer Intern

Ho Chi Minh, Vietnam Jun 2018 - Aug 2018

# **EDUCATION**

# **HCMVNU- University of Information Technology**

Ho Chi Minh, Vietnam

 $Bachelor\ of\ Engineering,\ Information\ system$ 

2016 - 2021

GPA: 9.1/10

Thesis: Constructing knowledgee graphs with triple extraction techniques

# Ben Tre High School for the gifted

Ben Tre, Vietnam

2013 - 2016

High School Diploma, Mathematics

GPA: 8.9/10

# SKILLS

**Data Engineering:** Python, Rust, SQL, Airflow, Kafka, Spark, AWS (S3, SQS, Athena, Redshift).

DevOps: CI/CD, Docker, Kubernetes.